<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Darren Wong</title>
 <link href="darrendub.comatom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="darrendub.com"/>
 <updated>2015-08-01T07:43:32-07:00</updated>
 <id>darrendub.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Darren Wong</name>
   <email>darrendavenwong@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Case Study - Paradise Soccer Club</title>
   <link href="darrendub.com/weblog/2015/08/01/2015-07-23-case-study-psc/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-01T07:43:31-07:00</updated>
   <id>darrendub.com/weblog/2015/08/01/2015-07-23-case-study-psc</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradise Soccer Club connects the beautiful game with the lifestyle of Hawai’i. I worked with PSC to build a website and e-commerce store to connect their brand to their fans across the world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Kick-off&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Max and I grew up in the same town in Hawaii but I didn’t get to know him until I moved away to San Francisco (funny how that happens). He played soccer with my best friend and that’s how we met. Hawaii does not have a professional sports teams, so many of its youth turn to the beautiful game as their favorite pastime. Max saw an opportunity to blend the culture of Hawaii with the sport of futbol, which is how Paradise Soccer Club began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with his Instagram account which currently has 7,000+ followers but Max had bigger dreams. He opened his storefront in Kailua, Oahu on June 21, 2013 to open arms from the community. His social media presence and collaborations with Hawaii’s premier lifestyle brands exploded his reach. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly PSC isn’t just about selling merchandise, it’s about giving back to the community. He hosts soccer tournaments with cash prizes, he holds FIFA tournaments and gives away merchandise to its winners. His store and brand has been and will always be an ohana for those who love the beautiful game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Images/videos of events&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The lay of the land, why I was brought in&lt;/em&gt;
&amp;lt;!-- I was hired to create a website to tell the PSC story and connect those visitors to his products. In the process we developed a fully functioning marketing and commerce site. --&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Passing the ball&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started talking with Max in June 2013, we kicked a few emails back and forth and identified a lot of areas where I could help. It was clear he wanted a website, as a place to send his Instagram followers. As we spoke further he started to talk about his brand new storefront his own shop and producing his own branded merchandise. This website would also serve as a selling channel and would be a place to increase his marketing efforts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Place email correspondence here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that PSC is run and operated by Max alone. He doesn’t have content generators, inventory managers, marketing analysts, he didn’t even have a website. I was happy to help out a friend and excited to help push this brand forward. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by asking a few questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What do you want the site to achieve?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wanted to communicate his brand and his product offerings to his fans. He also wanted a place to sell his products. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Who is your target audience?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He identified that his core audience would be teens to twenty-somethings passionate about soccer. He also identified families as children getting interested in soccer could grow into customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Will you need to update it?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He didn&amp;#39;t have a need to update the sites code but wanted to actively post a blog portion about sales and events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What is the current site setup?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, PSC&amp;#39;s only digital presence was their Instagram account, which was very popular. A lot of traffic would be driven from his social media so it was important to really nail the mobile experience. He was using Godaddy to park his domain with no hosting. Here is the initial sitemap:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homepage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About Us&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact Us&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was defintely enough to get started. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Playing the game&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Starting on the site&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- *Solution: What did you do? This covers your process, your strategic prowess, your technical capabilities, your team dynamic, your style.* --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Phases&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started talking a couple days before the opening of his storefront it was clear we were not going to be able to release a fully functioning site before the launch. There was still a lot to talk about and a lot of direction to be hashed out. We decided to roll the site out in phases. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Phase One: The Great Image&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first phase was to announce the grand opening of the store front. Max wanted something: &amp;quot;Simple, clean, with logo front and center or a pic.&amp;quot; We had a tight turn around so I turned to Tumblr to quickly execute against the first phase. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://darrendub.com/public/img/2015-07-23-psc/phase-one.png&quot; alt=&quot;Phase One&quot; title=&quot;Phase One&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I even created a rotating slideshow that changed out the background image, this was out of scope but made the basic site a little more engaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Show animation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Phase Two: Fake it till you make it&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phase two was the first attempt to fulfill his need to update the blog, but not the rest of the site. He was very active on Instagram and I knew this would be the easiest way for him to post, I linked his account to tumblr so that everytime he posted to Instagram he had the option to post to his blog. This worked out pretty well and is still how the blog portion operates today. This second phase was also where I laid the ground work of the sites architecture. We were still using Tumblr for hosting and since we were not building a full fledged theme we were limited to its basic html/css capabilities... even external css was a struggle 😔 (more on that later). But it was enough to rough out some early ideas of the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://darrendub.com/public/img/2015-07-23-psc/phase-two.png&quot; alt=&quot;Phase Two&quot; title=&quot;Phase Two&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Phase Three: Goooool&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last and final phase was a full site with a complete e-commerce store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started by narrowing down the site map:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was time to graduate the site, taking it off tumblr and on to its own hosting, using SASS to build repeatable patterns, developing the story, and most importantly creating the store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Square Corners The Market&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When building the store I was looking into various options: Stripe, Shopify, and Snipcart. [chart of differences?] And while each had their merits, I discovered that he was already using Square in his store to sell his products and manage inventory. It made a lot of sense to tie into this system to keep everything in one place. Square makes it super easy to spin up an online store and you can generate embed codes for each item and from there it&amp;#39;s simple: You upload a few images, set the quantity, and boom you&amp;#39;re off selling. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Patterns&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to the wireframe stage and started to block out patterns I would be using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hero Image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Product Grid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image Grid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video Block&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type Treatment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the About Us page, we wanted to include a section about the events PSC hosted. He had a lot of great video content from these events and I wanted to make this section more immersive than an image of the event. We landed on an auto-looping video shot by &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/botoboyfilms&quot;&gt;Orrin Nakanelua&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://darrendub.com/public/img/2015-07-23-psc/video-block.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Video Block&quot; title=&quot;Video Block&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Finger Tips&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We identified his core audience as twenty-something using the social medias it was important that the site be optimized for mobile finger tips. I began building the patterns with mobile in mind and had a lot of fun exploring the navigation. The navigation element gracefully degrades to meet the various mobile sizes, check it out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Insert Navigation GIF&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;News Letters&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram was PSC&amp;#39;s main marketing channel. I wanted to introduce a secondary channel that would build a list of new customers, build relationships with existing customers, and reach them on all their mobile devices. I&amp;#39;m talking about electronic mail. With the help of Mailchimp we set up a simple input to capture email addresses with the hopes of running full campaigns through email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We launched the site in accordance with the first anniversary of the storefront opening. This was also during the 2014 Men&amp;#39;s World Cup. Max expertly timed a product release to coincide with the new site and the world cup. His Merica Jersey was very well received, it helped catapult the site and his brand during the launch and is still the top selling item in his outline store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- *Outcome: What were the results? Did you build a new audience? Strengthen and grow an existing one? Increase sales? Great. Data, please.* --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Scores&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How did we do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 responsive web pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storefront opened June 21, 2013&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online store opened August 08, 2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online store generated 2x revenue in first three days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First month 4,000+ views on the site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30,278 Total Pageviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most popular item online is the Merica Jersey (accounts for 40% of all sales)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connected his brand to fans across the U.S. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darren was extremely passionate about this product and offered many suggestions to help push my brand. He created a fully functioning site that I am happy with!
&lt;cite&gt;Max Anton, Founder, PSC&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!-- *Reflection: If a reader has stuck around to this point, you can trust them with a bit more vulnerability. Here’s where you share the insights and voices of individual team members — planners, designers, developers, even your client — through brief, focused reflections on the job. What worked? What didn’t? What doubts did you have? What surprised you? What would you have done differently had you more time or more knowledge at the beginning? What did you learn and how will you use that knowledge in the future? This, really, is the most important and substantial piece of the puzzle for a prospect. If they’re seriously evaluating, they’ve probably heard plenty in the problem → solution → outcome department, but your honest and sincere reflection upon it will be what helps them get to know you and want to work with you.* --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Yellow Card&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Or things I learned along the way&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Not all square&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Square didn&amp;#39;t come with a few drawbacks. One of them being that the actual payment does not actually happen on the paradisesoccerclub.com site. When a user clicks a product they very &lt;em&gt;subtly&lt;/em&gt; get redirected to the PSC Online shop on Square Market. While this is not terrible, it does introduce another step in the buying process and my focus was to minimize the experience of that step. Another issue arose with the the embedding of products on the store. The embded code used a bit of Javascript which took some time to call the products from Square and in most cases there could be a noticable lag of the items being generated on our site. I am looking into hosting the items on our end for a snappier web experience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all our decision to leverage square for the online store has been a good one. We&amp;#39;re using an existing platform that he is using in the physical store and we can depend on the security of a well-known payments company to handle the online and in-store purchases. Another huge reason for using Square is that it managed product fulfillment all in the same web app. Which is great because Max only needs to go to one place to get information about sales, inventory, and orders. Easy peasy.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- After discussing our options, Max and I were in agreement that this was still a viable option because Square would be responsible for backend credit card transaction and updating the product inventory.  --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Stop trying to make newsletter happen&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While building the site I thought it would be great to begin capturing email addresses in hopes of being about to build an active funnel/cycle to market to existing customers and new customers. I used mailchimp which couldn&amp;#39;t of been simplier. I linked a form input to a mailchimp generated landing page and voila we were capturing potential customers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where we went wrong. Max didn&amp;#39;t fully commit to generating content through email. After all it takes a lot of time and effort to create, deliver, and nurture amazing campaigns. We sent two emails total which were well recieved but our list is still too small to make an impact. In the future I&amp;#39;d like to help him stream line this process, possibly generating emails from his Instagram account. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Phases, or nah&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think rolling the site out in phases was a great idea. It helped Max get his feet wet into his brand new website. However it took a while to reach the final site because it introduced some technical debt early on. I needed to get the site out fast so using tumblr was a no-brainer. However, when it was time to build the actual site I was not able to leverage most of the code base (a lot of interal css styles and strange markup). I think if I had asked more pointed questions up front I could have identified his needs quickly and we would have arrived at the brand new site sooner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;First&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first experience getting hired to develop a full site. It was very exciting and I learned a lot along the way. I&amp;#39;m looking forward to doing more work like this in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wireframes</title>
   <link href="darrendub.com/weblog/2015/07/07/wireframes/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>darrendub.com/weblog/2015/07/07/wireframes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I began to sketch out the wireframes for my site, two pages in particular stood out to me: the home page and work page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-07-07-wireframes/wireframes-paper.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframe Sketches&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Site Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Home&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Work&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Words&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;About&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Home&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For obvious reasons the homepage is important; it’s most likely the first introduction to me and my work. And it&amp;#39;s the page that&amp;#39;s usually tied to the top level domain, so I became particularly interested in how I&amp;#39;d show my work on the homepage. I boiled it down to three elements: copy, image, and background image. The copy and image will sit on the background image, though there will have to be some interplay between the three. I will create that interplay by using static assets and possibly using animation or gifs to add further interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-07-07-wireframes/wireframes-work-pattern.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframe Work Pattern&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s important that these all feel like a cohesive pattern—that each element not only works well with other elements but enhances the next. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the full wireframe for the homepage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-07-07-wireframes/wireframes-home.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframe Home&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recurring theme throughout my &lt;a href=&quot;/weblog/2015/05/21/website-inspiration/&quot;&gt;inspiration&lt;/a&gt; was well articulated case studies. It&amp;#39;s important to me to be able to explain design decisions, showing the variations and iterations that led to the final design. This is something I still need to work on and one of the main reasons I am doing this &lt;a href=&quot;/weblog/2015/04/15/open-redesign/&quot;&gt;live redesign&lt;/a&gt;—to work on synthesizing my process and clearly explaining design directions. My work page will be created with long form reading in mind, using text treatment and images to keep the reader engaged throughout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-07-07-wireframes/wireframes-work.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframe Work&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I have a foundation to build off of, I am going to dive into the code. I will start by developing the grid, then style my typography, and finally build the various modules for each pattern. Wireframes are never meant to be the final blueprint, and I am sure that I will deviate from what I’ve sketched above once I get into the code. I am excited to get into the code and building this thing! You can watch live here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://darrendub.com&quot;&gt;darrendub.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Example content</title>
   <link href="darrendub.com/2015/05/21/2014-01-01-example-content/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-21T10:30:02-07:00</updated>
   <id>darrendub.com/2015/05/21/2014-01-01-example-content</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;
  Howdy! This is an example blog post that shows several types of HTML content supported in this theme.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;dis parturient montes&lt;/a&gt;, nascetur ridiculus mus. &lt;em&gt;Aenean eu leo quam.&lt;/em&gt; Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum. Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Nullam id dolor id nibh ultricies vehicula ut id elit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Etiam porta &lt;strong&gt;sem malesuada magna&lt;/strong&gt; mollis euismod. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Inline HTML elements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTML defines a long list of available inline tags, a complete list of which can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element&quot;&gt;Mozilla Developer Network&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To bold text&lt;/strong&gt;, use &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;To italicize text&lt;/em&gt;, use &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abbreviations, like &lt;abbr title=&quot;HyperText Markup Langage&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/abbr&gt; should use &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;abbr&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, with an optional &lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; attribute for the full phrase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citations, like &lt;cite&gt;&amp;mdash; Mark otto&lt;/cite&gt;, should use &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;cite&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Deleted&lt;/del&gt; text should use &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;del&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;ins&gt;inserted&lt;/ins&gt; text should use &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ins&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Superscript &lt;sup&gt;text&lt;/sup&gt; uses &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;sup&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and subscript &lt;sub&gt;text&lt;/sub&gt; uses &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of these elements are styled by browsers with few modifications on our part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Heading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vivamus sagittis lacus vel augue rutrum faucibus dolor auctor. Duis mollis, est non commodo luctus, nisi erat porttitor ligula, eget lacinia odio sem nec elit. Morbi leo risus, porta ac consectetur ac, vestibulum at eros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis &lt;code&gt;code element&lt;/code&gt; montes, nascetur ridiculus mus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot; data-lang=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Example can be run directly in your JavaScript console&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Create a function that takes two arguments and returns the sum of those arguments&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;adder&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;Function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;a&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;b&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;return a + b&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Call the function&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;adder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// &amp;gt; 8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur. Etiam porta sem malesuada magna mollis euismod. Fusce dapibus, tellus ac cursus commodo, tortor mauris condimentum nibh, ut fermentum massa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Gists via GitHub Pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vestibulum id ligula porta felis euismod semper. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Donec sed odio dui.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/5555251.js?file=gist.md&quot;&gt; &lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aenean eu leo quam. Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Donec sed odio dui. Vestibulum id ligula porta felis euismod semper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur. Etiam porta sem malesuada magna mollis euismod. Fusce dapibus, tellus ac cursus commodo, tortor mauris condimentum nibh, ut fermentum massa justo sit amet risus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Praesent commodo cursus magna, vel scelerisque nisl consectetur et.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donec id elit non mi porta gravida at eget metus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donec ullamcorper nulla non metus auctor fringilla. Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vestibulum id ligula porta felis euismod semper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maecenas sed diam eget risus varius blandit sit amet non magna.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;HyperText Markup Language (HTML)&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;The language used to describe and define the content of a Web page&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Used to describe the appearance of Web content&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;JavaScript (JS)&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;The programming language used to build advanced Web sites and applications&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integer posuere erat a ante venenatis dapibus posuere velit aliquet. Morbi leo risus, porta ac consectetur ac, vestibulum at eros. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quisque consequat sapien eget quam rhoncus, sit amet laoreet diam tempus. Aliquam aliquam metus erat, a pulvinar turpis suscipit at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://placehold.it/800x400&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder&quot; title=&quot;Large example image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://placehold.it/400x200&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder&quot; title=&quot;Medium example image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://placehold.it/200x200&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder&quot; title=&quot;Small example image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Tables&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Upvotes&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Downvotes&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tfoot&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Totals&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;21&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tfoot&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Alice&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Bob&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Charlie&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nullam id dolor id nibh ultricies vehicula ut id elit. Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to see something else added? &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/poole/issues/new&quot;&gt;Open an issue.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Website Inspiration</title>
   <link href="darrendub.com/weblog/2015/05/21/website-inspiration/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>darrendub.com/weblog/2015/05/21/website-inspiration</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://neverbland.com/&quot;&gt;Neverbland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beautiful collection of work and a great use of the grid &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-depth, thoughtful case studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can really tell that they love what they do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-05-21-website-inspiration/never-bland-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Neverbland Homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugeinc.com/&quot;&gt;Huge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HUGE typography!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personality and color make the site alive and vibrant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rigid grid that can adapt based on content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-05-21-website-inspiration/huge-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Huge Nike&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-05-21-website-inspiration/huge-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Huge Harvard Business Revieww&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://beta.rallyinteractive.com/&quot;&gt;Rally&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site is snappy, just feels good to the click &amp;amp; scroll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of personality, can sense the love that went into the site and the work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Big type, big colors, big personality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go into great detail within their case studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subtle, delightful animations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-05-21-website-inspiration/rally-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rally National Parks&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-05-21-website-inspiration/rally-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rally National Parks Case Study&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://weightshift.com/&quot;&gt;Weightshift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interesting use of a fixed left sidebar in case studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impressive, well articulated work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I love the &amp;quot;Our Work&amp;quot; section at the end of each case study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hero images and information lockup is really well done and help lead your eye down the page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-05-21-website-inspiration/weightshift-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Weightshift Homepage&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-05-21-website-inspiration/weightshift-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Weightshift Rdio Case Study&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://papermodelplane.com/&quot;&gt;Paper Model Plane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background image transitions are so slick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numbers project is amazing, great use of images, video, and grid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple and clean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-05-21-website-inspiration/papermodelplane.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Paper Model Plane Homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://paulstamatiou.com/&quot;&gt;Paul Stamatiou&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Really in-depth case studies, really&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I love the twitter modal that subtly slides up, beckoning you to tweet (if you like it put a tweet on it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;His photos and grid are just gorgeous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-05-21-website-inspiration/stammy-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Paul Stamatiou Photosets&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-05-21-website-inspiration/stammy-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Paul Stamatiou Twitter Video Case Study&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teehanlax.com/&quot;&gt;Teehan + Lax&lt;/a&gt; (R.I.P. 🙏😭)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Case studies are very genuine they offer not only the design decisions made but the feelings and heart that went into each project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I love the different viewpoints of the &amp;#39;What We Learned&amp;#39; sections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Big beautiful typography gets me every time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of interactivity for each case study that reveal the immense depth of their work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-05-21-website-inspiration/teehanlax-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Teehan + Lax Readability Case Study&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015-05-21-website-inspiration/teehanlax-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Teehan + Lax  Medium Case Study&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While writing this article I learned that I want my site to have a few things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I love, love, love &lt;strong&gt;large typography&lt;/strong&gt;. I think when done right it guides the viewer&amp;#39;s eyes while helping them come to a nice pause as they read through a piece of text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case studies&lt;/strong&gt; that pull back the curtains to reveal the heart of the designer and her decisions are really inspiring to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am really drawn to &lt;strong&gt;grids&lt;/strong&gt; that are rigid in structure but flexible to adapt to the needs of the content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having &lt;strong&gt;personality&lt;/strong&gt; is simple in theory but difficult to implement as it is embedded in every aspect of your site and your work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m feeling super inspired after looking at all these examples and next is to get sketchy with some &lt;a href=&quot;/weblog/2015/07/07/wireframes/&quot;&gt;wireframes&lt;/a&gt; and start thinking about the content for my case studies!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Inventory</title>
   <link href="darrendub.com/weblog/2015/05/16/2015-05-16-inventory/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-16T17:28:07-07:00</updated>
   <id>darrendub.com/weblog/2015/05/16/2015-05-16-inventory</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was late February of 2012, I walked into the Design Lab at the University of San Francisco, sat down in a gray office chair, took a deep sigh and opened Adobe Dreamweaver. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The events that followed are very cloudy but I emerged from my stupor with a place on the web to talk about my projects that I have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Tools I used&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FTP: Fetch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text Editor: Textwrangler / Dreamweaver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain: Godaddy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hosting: HostMonster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Languages: HTML, Vanilla CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tools are not inherently bad, the way I strung them all together is at fault. I would begin writing code in Textwrangler, transfer to Dreamweaver (I have no idea why), use Dreamweaver to make black magic, then drag that into Fetch, voilá a website. I had no real version control, no testing, looking back on it now it felt like I just threw it up and hoped that nothing was broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was the old me, this is the new me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Tools I will use&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FTP: N/A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text Editor: Sublime Text 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain: Namecheap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hosting: Github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markup: HTML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preprocessor: Sass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post-processor: Autoprefixer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compiler: Codekit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image Optimizing: Tiny PNG, Image Optium, Image Alpha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CDN: Github?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Version Control: Github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance: Webpagetest, PageSpeed Insights, CSS Stats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Performance Boss</title>
   <link href="darrendub.com/weblog/2015/05/04/performance-boss/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>darrendub.com/weblog/2015/05/04/performance-boss</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paid tha Cost to Be da Bo$$&lt;/em&gt; was the sixth album by American rapper Snoop Dogg. As you listen to the album a certain theme begins to emerge: success is only attained through hard work. In a &lt;em&gt;dev-signers&lt;/em&gt; world, that hard work might look like ensuring your site performs well. Snoop would know what it takes to be a great developer, just as &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@darrendub/6-reasons-why-drake-would-be-a-great-designer-530ee138ea35&quot;&gt;Drake knows what it takes to be a great designer&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be the performance bo$$ I need a &lt;a href=&quot;http://danielmall.com/articles/how-to-make-a-performance-budget/&quot;&gt;performance budget&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimal Site Specs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Page Weight: 270kb &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start Render: 1.2s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fully Loaded: 2.8s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And a speed index score as close to 1000 as possible (hah)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page Weight Breakdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTML: 50kb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CSS: 80kb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images: 140kb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total: 270kb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These conservative numbers aren&amp;#39;t meant to hinder, they are meant to guide me down a path where I can be aware of the correlation between my design and how people will view it. Dan Mall says it best:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe designers do their best work within constraints.
&lt;cite&gt;- Dan Mall&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth Dan, truth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another man who speaks truths; Tim Kaldec, collects four &lt;a href=&quot;http://timkadlec.com/2014/11/performance-budget-metrics/&quot;&gt;performance budget metrics&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://timkadlec.com/2014/11/performance-budget-metrics/#milestone-timings&quot;&gt;Milestone timings&lt;/a&gt;:
The experience of loading a page, things like load time and render time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://timkadlec.com/2014/11/performance-budget-metrics/#speedindex&quot;&gt;SpeedIndex&lt;/a&gt;:
This metric is based on how it feels to load a page. If a page fully renders in 5 seconds but serves content in under a second, it feels faster and would rank well on SpeedIndex.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://timkadlec.com/2014/11/performance-budget-metrics/#quantity-based&quot;&gt;Quantity based metrics&lt;/a&gt;:
Things like page weight and image weight mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://timkadlec.com/2014/11/performance-budget-metrics/#rule-based&quot;&gt;Rule Based&lt;/a&gt;:
Defined by PageSpeed score and YSlow score, they don&amp;#39;t provide an in-depth account of your site but serve as a nice checklist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will attempt to stay within the metrics listed here as they will give me a website that feels lightening to the tap (or click). These limitations will give me laser focus when designing, guiding me toward a design that is beautiful and functional. However, I do have my doubts that it will be too limiting. I&amp;#39;m worried I will not explore every avenue because I need to stay within these guidelines. The inverse is also true, Dan Mall writes that designers crave constrictions as it helps produce better work. Coal is put under immense pressure to become a diamond and that is what I want to create, a diamond 💎.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reference Links:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tim Kaldec: &lt;a href=&quot;http://timkadlec.com/2014/11/performance-budget-metrics/&quot;&gt;Performance Budget Metrics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dan Mall: &lt;a href=&quot;http://danielmall.com/articles/how-to-make-a-performance-budget/&quot;&gt;How To Make A Performance Budget&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Katie Kovalcin: &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/katiekovalcin/the-path-to-performance&quot;&gt;The Path To Performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paul Irish: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R8W_6xWphtw&quot;&gt;Delivering The Goods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CDNIFY: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdnify.com/discover/web-performance-guide&quot;&gt;A Guide to Optimising Website &amp;amp; Application Performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tutsplus: &lt;a href=&quot;http://webdesign.tutsplus.com/articles/best-practices-for-increasing-website-performance--webdesign-9109&quot;&gt;Best Practices for Increasing Website Performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What’s Working & What Isn’t</title>
   <link href="darrendub.com/weblog/2015/05/01/whats-working/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>darrendub.com/weblog/2015/05/01/whats-working</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here is my &lt;a href=&quot;http://darrendavenwong.com&quot;&gt;old site&lt;/a&gt; in all of its glory. Take it all in. Look at the fixed grid, the tiled thumbnails, and embrace the gray background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s working:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimal, “clean” layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s responsive (&lt;em&gt;chuckles&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still like these pieces of work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The about me section is kinda funny?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Page Weight

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTML: 3.1kb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CSS: 3.4kb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Font: 32kb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JS: 39kb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMG: 270kb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total: 347.5 kb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speed

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start Render:      0.891s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fully Loaded:      1.573s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speed Index:      1048&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requests:           16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tests

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webpagetest.org/result/150422_36_130P/&quot;&gt;Webpagetest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/?url=darrendavenwong.com&quot;&gt;PageSpeed Insights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What isn’t working:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Personality

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holy gray background batman, looks like the inside of Karl the Fog, #e6e6e6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been described as lively and outgoing this website looks the underside of a shoe&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Case Studies Lack Substance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where are the compelling write ups? I care about my work but the way I talk about it on my site doesn’t correctly portray that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The layout of the case studies are hard to read&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code is literally from someone else&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sorry &lt;a href=&quot;https://andytaylor.me/2013/04/09/1140px-css-grid-retired/&quot;&gt;Andy Taylor’s 1140px grid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Projects are dated&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do these projects show my skill set? Hayl no&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Poor Optimization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Caching Static Images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images are not compressed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No CDN (Do I really need one?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Version Control&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I write HTML and CSS locally and drag it into my FTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No conflict errors or warnings in CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s instantly live, no testing environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok. Ok. I know I’m being very critical of my site which was made circa 2012 and to be fair it’s done some nice things. It loads fairly quickly, those are the metrics I’m reaching for with the new site (which may be a little unrealistic). I think it started to introduce my personality and style. Also just to kinda show where my head was at while making this site, I was taught Dreamweaver was the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; way to make websites...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.amazon.com/images/G/01/software/detail-page/B003B32A88-1.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;Yucky &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Adobe-Dreamweaver-CS5-Old-Version/dp/B003B32AA6&quot;&gt;via Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Next steps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be a good foundation to build my new home. Next, is to formulate the blueprint buy starting with a solid &lt;a href=&quot;/weblog/2015/05/04/performance-boss/&quot;&gt;performance plan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Redesign Brief</title>
   <link href="darrendub.com/weblog/2015/04/17/redesign-brief/"/>
   <updated>2015-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>darrendub.com/weblog/2015/04/17/redesign-brief</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most difficult challenges designers face today is the inability to create for ourselves (or at least be satisfied with the things we create). This issue has roots that trace back to the world’s earliest designers who used cave walls to display their mock ups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/f/f4/SantaCruz-CuevaManos-P2210651b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cueva de las Manos&quot; title=&quot;Cueva de las Manos&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:SantaCruz-CuevaManos-P2210651b.jpg&quot;&gt;Marianocecowski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take note of the many hands over lapping. You can imagine the internal struggle of this primordial designer saying, &lt;em&gt;“Are there too many hands?&lt;/em&gt;...&lt;em&gt;What do the hands look like on mobile?&lt;/em&gt;...&lt;em&gt;Fred, I think I need a complete overhaul, a redesign.”&lt;/em&gt; It’s in our blood to continue to redefine ourselves, to push our creative abilities, to forever carry the burden of being incomplete. This insatiable desire to hold the highest of standards of our own work is not ill fated, it drives us and makes us stronger, better, faster... stronger?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I share much of the same internal struggles of our ancestral counterpart. My website is not something I’m happy with and I know I can do better, and yesterday turned to my friend and said, &lt;em&gt;“Fred, I think I need a complete overhaul, a redesign.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However instead of designing in a cave, I’m going to design out in the open. I’m going to bring you all along as I go, to keep me in check, to send me happy notes and most importantly give me feedback early and often. This will also be an experiment to discover my process (which has never before been documented, until now). So come along and lets do this thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Project Summary:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to create a fast, responsive, delightful experience on the web to showcase my work. I will have a blog to document my thoughts about design and other musings. The site will also increase my presence and friendships on twitter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Goals&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliver a new site in 4 months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase website performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase engagement on social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop in depth case studies for my work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a blog to write about design and development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Measures of Success:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Performance:&lt;/em&gt; A user should begin to see the website rendering in 100ms. This should produce a speed index score of 1000ms and to get there my site should deliver the critical path view in the first 14kb of the page. (via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R8W_6xWphtw&quot;&gt;Paul Irish&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blog:&lt;/em&gt; 1,000 Visits, Post twice a week&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter:&lt;/em&gt; 10 new followers, 40 Shares&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design:&lt;/em&gt; High fives from colleagues&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Happiness:&lt;/em&gt; A site that I am proud of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Schedule:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My schedule for this project is going to be a little further out than a traditional website project. Unfortunately, this redesign will not be the only thing I’m working on. I have a full time job (we’re &lt;a href=&quot;http://grnh.se/j2e8bl&quot;&gt;hiring&lt;/a&gt;), a full time girlfriend (she’s not hiring), and a part time side project (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smokedmeatsaturdays.com/&quot;&gt;Smoked Meat Saturdays&lt;/a&gt;). I want to give this redesign a fighting chance of coming to fruition. I’m also an advocate of the under promise, over deliver policy... ya let’s go with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research (2 weeks)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s Working and What Isn’t &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand Audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze Current Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early Wireframes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site Architecture &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Craft tools/environment I will use
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Content (2 weeks)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Develop Case Studies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write Blog Posts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;SEO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;About page&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feedback
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Design (6 weeks)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exploration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspiration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modular Thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mock-up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prototype&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily Sharable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Input&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early and Often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peers and mentors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feedback&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update with inputs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slight Polish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare for Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feedback
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Development (6 weeks)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modular Code&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Small First&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delight/Animation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Extensible Patterns&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Style Guide?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Layout Optimization Guide&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feedback
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Testing (2 weeks)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Performance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Performance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Performance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bugs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feedback
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Launch (Should be immediate since I’m designing in the open!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ongoing Maintenance 
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to walk away from this project with a website that I am proud of. A website that is fast loading. A website that makes use of a system of design patterns and modular code. A website that is set in beautiful (legible) type. A website that is set with beautiful words that communicate my work and who I am. I think I will learn a lot from this process and I can’t wait to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Links&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.upanup.com/website-timeline-a-plan-for-success/&quot;&gt;Upanup Studios - Website Timeline: A Plan for Success&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://timkadlec.com/2014/11/performance-budget-metrics/&quot;&gt;Tim Kadlec - Performance Budget Metrics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Open Redesign</title>
   <link href="darrendub.com/weblog/2015/04/15/open-redesign/"/>
   <updated>2015-04-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>darrendub.com/weblog/2015/04/15/open-redesign</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey there, my name is Darren and I design things for the Internet and people like you. I will be using this space to document the open redesign of my brand new site! I am doing this for a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build some momentum to redesign my current &lt;a href=&quot;http://darrendavenwong.com&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share my process and learn from that process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get input early and often from viewers like you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be accountable for delivering a brand spanking new site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be using this &lt;a href=&quot;/timeline/&quot;&gt;timeline&lt;/a&gt; to keep track of my updates and this &lt;a href=&quot;/weblog/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; to post articles, snippets and thoughts as I develop my site. I make things for the web and want to share how I make those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/weblog/2015/04/17/redesign-brief/&quot;&gt;Here is the full redesign brief &amp;#8594;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designing in the open is not a new idea, great &lt;em&gt;dev-signers&lt;/em&gt; like &lt;a href=&quot;http://bradfrost.com/blog/post/designing-in-the-open/&quot;&gt;Brad Frost&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://danielmall.com/articles/rif-element-collages/&quot;&gt;Dan Mall&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/screencasting-complete-redesign-get-access-kickstarter/&quot;&gt;Chris Coyier&lt;/a&gt;, have used this technique to utilize our great open community to help further their design decisions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an awesome live redesign of CodePen by Sparkbox happening now! &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.seesparkbox.com/&quot;&gt;Check it out &amp;#8594;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;By sharing your thoughts, your successes, your failures, your techniques, your process, your resources, you’re able to have a much greater impact on the world than whatever happens to be in your project’s scope.
    &lt;cite&gt;- Brad Frost&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m nervous and excited to get started. I think this will be fun exercise to push my skills and develop my confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darren&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/darrendub&quot;&gt;@darrendub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
