<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Darren Daven Wong</title>
 <link href="/weblogatom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="/weblog"/>
 <updated>2015-04-14T10:35:47-07:00</updated>
 <id></id>
 <author>
   <name>Darren Wong</name>
   <email>darrendavenwong@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Why are you doing this?</title>
   <link href="/weblog/2015/04/15/why-are-you-doing-this/"/>
   <updated>2015-04-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>/2015/04/15/why-are-you-doing-this</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey there, my name is Darren and I design things for the internet and people like you. I will be using this space to document the live redesign of my brand new site! I am doing this for a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build some momentum to redesign my current &lt;a href=&quot;http://darrendavenwong.com&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share my process and learn from that process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get input early and often from viewers like you&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be accountable for delivering a brand spanking new site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be using this &lt;a href=&quot;/weblog/timeline/index.html&quot;&gt;timeline&lt;/a&gt; to keep track of my updates and this blog to post articles, snippets and thoughts as I develop my site. I make things for the web and want to share how I make those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designing in the open is not a new idea, great devsigners like &lt;a href=&quot;http://bradfrost.com/blog/post/designing-in-the-open/&quot;&gt;Brad Frost&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://danielmall.com/articles/rif-element-collages/&quot;&gt;Dan Mall&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/screencasting-complete-redesign-get-access-kickstarter/&quot;&gt;Chris Coyier&lt;/a&gt; to name a few, have used this technique to utilize our great open community to help further their deisign decisions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an awesome live redesign of CodePen by Sparkbox happening now! &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.seesparkbox.com/&quot;&gt;Check it out →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;By sharing your thoughts, your successes, your failures, your techniques, your process, your resources, you’re able to have a much greater impact on the world than whatever happens to be in your project’s scope.
	&lt;cite&gt;- Brad Frost&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deliver a new site in six months&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop in depth case studies for my work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop a blog to write about design and development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increase engangement on social media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increase website performance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a website I am proud of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m nervous and excited to get started. I think this will be fun exercise to push my skills and develop my confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darren&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/darrendub&quot;&gt;@darrendub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
